
 <?xml version="1.0" ?> 
- <books>
- <book id="001">
  <isbn>0465044050</isbn> 
  <title>Birth of the Mind</title> 
  <firstname>Gary</firstname> 
  <lastname>Marcus</lastname> 
  <publisher>Basic Books</publisher> 
  <year>2004</year> 
  <price>17.68</price> 
  <picture>0465044050.gif</picture> 
  <description>The first book to show precisely how genes build the wonders of the human brain, and why the Human Genome project could radically alter our view of the world. Scientists have struggled to understand how a tiny number of genes could contain the instructions for building the human brain, arguably the most complex device in the known universe. Synthesizing up-to-the-minute biology with his own original findings on child development, Marcus dispels the common misconceptions people harbor about genes, and explores the stunning implications of this research for the future of genetic engineering.</description> 
  </book>
- <book id="002">
  <isbn>0192860925</isbn> 
  <title>The Selfish Gene</title> 
  <firstname>Richard</firstname> 
  <lastname>Dawkins</lastname> 
  <publisher>Oxford University Press</publisher> 
  <year>1990</year> 
  <price>10.47</price> 
  <picture>0192860925.gif</picture> 
  <description>Inheriting the mantle of revolutionary biologist from Darwin, Watson, and Crick, Richard Dawkins forced an enormous change in the way we see ourselves and the world with the publication of The Selfish Gene. Suppose, instead of thinking about organisms using genes to reproduce themselves, as we had since Mendel's work was rediscovered, we turn it around and imagine that our genes build and maintain us in order to make more genes. That simple reversal seems to answer many puzzlers which had stumped scientists for years, and we haven't thought of evolution in the same way since.</description> 
  </book>
- <book id="003">
  <isbn>0375412883</isbn> 
  <title>The Fabric of the Cosmos</title> 
  <firstname>Brian</firstname> 
  <lastname>Greene</lastname> 
  <publisher>Knopf</publisher> 
  <year>2004</year> 
  <price>19.69</price> 
  <picture>0375412883.gif</picture> 
  <description>Focusing on the enigma of time, Greene establishes that nothing in the laws of physics insists that it run in any particular direction and that "time's arrow" is a relic of the universe's condition at the moment of the big bang. And in explaining the big bang itself, Greene shows how recent cutting-edge developments in superstring and M-theory may reconcile the behavior of everything from the smallest particle to the largest black hole. This startling vision culminates in a vibrant eleven-dimensional "multiverse," pulsating with ever-changing textures, where space and time themselves may dissolve into subtler, more fundamental entities.</description> 
  </book>
- <book id="004">
  <isbn>0674002350</isbn> 
  <title>Sociobiology: The New Synthesis</title> 
  <firstname>Edward</firstname> 
  <lastname>Wilson</lastname> 
  <publisher>Belknap Press</publisher> 
  <year>2000</year> 
  <price>19.56</price> 
  <picture>0674002350.gif</picture> 
  <description>When this classic work was first published in 1975, it created a new discipline and started a tumultuous round in the age-old nature versus nurture debate. Although voted by officers and fellows of the international Animal Behavior Society the most important book on animal behavior of all time, Sociobiology is probably more widely known as the object of bitter attacks by social scientists and other scholars who opposed its claim that human social behavior, indeed human nature, has a biological foundation.</description> 
  </book>
- <book id="005">
  <isbn>0142001783</isbn> 
  <title>Synaptic Self</title> 
  <firstname>Joseph</firstname> 
  <lastname>LeDoux</lastname> 
  <publisher>Penguin Books</publisher> 
  <year>2003</year> 
  <price>11.20</price> 
  <picture>0142001783.gif</picture> 
  <description>To Joseph LeDoux, the simple question, "What makes us who we are?" represents the driving force behind his 20-plus years of research into the cognitive, emotional, and motivational functions of the brain. LeDoux believes the answer rests in the synapses, key players in the brain's intricately designed communication system. In other words, the pathways by which a person's "hardwired" responses (nature) mesh with his or her unique life experiences (nurture) determine that person's individuality. Here, LeDoux nimbly compresses centuries of philosophy, psychology, and biology into an amazingly clear picture of humanity's journey toward understanding the self.</description> 
  </book>
- <book id="006">
  <isbn>0262632683</isbn> 
  <title>The Algebraic Mind</title> 
- <author>
  <firstname>Gary</firstname> 
  <lastname>Marcus</lastname> 
  </author>
  <publisher>Bradford Books</publisher> 
  <year>2003</year> 
  <price>19.25</price> 
  <picture>0262632683.gif</picture> 
  <description>In "The Algebraic Mind" Gary Marcus attempts to integrate two theories about how the mind works, one that says that the mind is a computer-like manipulator of symbols, and another that says that the mind is a large network of neurons working together in parallel. Resisting the conventional wisdom that says that if the mind is a large neural network it cannot simultaneously be a manipulator of symbols, Marcus outlines a variety of ways in which neural systems could be organized so as to manipulate symbols, and he shows why such systems are more likely to provide an adequate substrate for language and cognition than neural systems that are inconsistent with the manipulation of symbols.</description> 
  </book>
- <book id="007">
  <isbn>0375708111</isbn> 
  <title>The Elegant Universe</title> 
- <author>
  <firstname>Brian</firstname> 
  <lastname>Greene</lastname> 
  </author>
  <publisher>Vintage</publisher> 
  <year>2000</year> 
  <price>11.17</price> 
  <picture>0375708111.gif</picture> 
  <description>In a rare blend of scientific insight and writing as elegant as the theories it explains, Brian Greene, one of the world's leading string theorists, peels away the layers of mystery surrounding string theory to reveal a universe that consists of 11 dimensions where the fabric of space tears and repairs itself, and all matter-from the smallest quarks to the most gargantuan supernovas-is generated by the vibrations of microscopically tiny loops of energy. Green uses everything from an amusement park ride to ants on a garden hose to illustrate the beautiful yet bizarre realities that modern physics is unveiling.</description> 
  </book>
  </books>